PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
盒子中的皮克斯 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Welcome to Pixar.
欢迎来到皮克斯
In the next lesson you'll learn to rig your own character.
在接下来的课程中你将学习如何绑定你的角色
(drum and cymbal clash)
(鼓声和锣声)
If you've gone through the animation lesson,
如果你之前参加过动画课程
you've already learned how to
你已经学习了
create an animated performance of a bouncing ball.
如何给一个弹跳的小球创建动画表演
We gave you controls which allowed you to
我们给你提供了控制器
move the ball around, and stretch it like this,
让你能够这样移动和拉伸小球
or squash it like that.
或者这样挤压它
These transformations are defined by different
这些变形是由不同种类的变形器描述的
For example, a rotate deformer will
例如 一个旋转变形器
let you rotate the ball, a translate deformer will
让你能够旋转小球 一个移动变形器
allow you to move the ball in any direction,
能够让你朝任何方向移动小球
and a scale deformer can be used to
一个缩放变形器能够被用于
squash the ball when it hits the ground.
在小球着地时挤压小球
Figuring out and creating these deformers is
装配和创建这些变形器
the job of a rigger.
是绑定师的工作
It's pretty simple when done with a ball.
绑定一个小球非常简单
It gets a lot more complicated when dealing with a car.
绑定一辆车就会变得更加复杂
And a human baby is really hard.
而绑定一个人类婴儿则非常困难
As you can see, I'm standing next to this giant lamp,
就如你看到的 我站在这个巨大的台灯旁边
who was featured in Luxo Jr.,
它曾经出现在《小台灯》里
one of the first short films made at Pixar.
这是皮克斯创作的第一个短片
Although lamps are just solid objects without
尽管台灯只是一个坚硬的物体
their own movement or emotions,
没有自身的运动和情感
a young animator named John Lasseter believed
一个年轻的动画师 约翰·拉塞特
he could make it into an actor.
相信他能够让它成为一个角色
He saw how this lamp could become
他看到了只要给这个台灯一些简单的绑定
a lifelike character if it was given a simple rig.
就能赋予他无限生命的可能性
This rig is made up of deformers that
绑定由一些变形器组成
can make the lamp rotate, translate, and scale.
它们能够让台灯旋转、移动和缩放
In 1986, a rigging artist named Evan Auspie
1986年 绑定师 Evan Auspie
had to work extremely hard to create
需要竭尽所能地去创建
the software that would rig the lamp,
一个能够绑定台灯的软件
and allow John to create his animated performance.
让约翰能够去创造动画表演
In the rest of this lesson, you will get to
在接下来的的课程中
create the rig which will allow us to animate our lamp.
你将会创建一个绑定 以便能够让我们给台灯调动画
Before we rig our lamp, we need to examine him closely.
在绑定台灯之前 我们需要测试一下它
You'll notice that it consists of a base,
你会发现它包含了一个底座
a mid, and a lamp head.
一个台灯杆和一个灯罩
And this is connected by joints that rotate.
它们被可旋转的关节所连接
And what you'll notice is that
你会发现
one rotational deformer will move a joint,
一个旋转变形器将会
which causes it to rotate, and there is
让关节能够旋转
some dependence of the other joints upon that rotation.
而且一些从属关节也会跟随它转动
Dependence of one part on another is
一个部分从属于另一个部分
what we call a hierarchy.
我们称之为继承
And it's our job as a rigger to
绑定师的工作之一
determine what that hierarchy is.
就是确定继承关系
So that when one joint rotates,
因此当一个关节旋转时
all the other joints will follow.
其他所有的关节都将会跟随
In this first exercise, let's rig our lamp with
在第一个练习中 让我们使用我们说过的简单旋转
the simple rotations we talked about.
去绑定这个台灯
You would do this by dragging
我们拖拽旋转变形器
the rotate deformers onto each of the joints.
到每个关节
With just four rotates, it is possible to
只要4个旋转变形器
create poses that express a wide range of
就可以创建能够表达
emotions and actions.
各种不同的感情和动作的姿势
Typically a rigger will test a rig by
通常一个绑定师会这样进行绑定测试
creating a number of poses that
去创建一些
will show off what the rig can do.
能够展示绑定能够做什么的姿势
(laughter)
(笑)
These people are also riggers. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
这人也是绑定师 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox